■
人人影视POI小分队倾情奉献  翻译：王小麦大战西装侠  紫杉爱卡姐伟光正  紫玉主控天下  卫老哥撒腿就跑人  CiciXT时刻警惕偷狗贼  幸田实果子给肖爷跪  free维塔豪购肖根牌熨斗  面条包子吃饭睡觉打豆豆  艾瑞卡遛小熊  宅女之后变身御姐佐伊  桑桑怒收德西玛  时间轴：凭陵新月抱紧宅总大腿  阿包啪啪陶贱贱  兜兜兜爹心疼机器宝宝  雪贵人对皮富豪负责一辈子  Sagesage拜老师考试无敌   后期&特效：灰灰誓死捍卫根妹   翻&校&总监：阿好・RF大旗永不倒   鸣谢： zz  Alex
纽约城已陷入黑暗两小时了
Two hours have passed since the city of New York plunged into darkness.
搜寻系统管理员
搜寻区域
纽约市
摄像头信号 下线
手机信号 下线
网络信号 下线
当局尚未排除是恐怖袭击的可能性
Authorities have not yet ruled out the possibility of a terrorist attack.
■
来源  RYLA科技S7卫星调制解调器
上行线路  DT-11地球同步卫星
检测到传输异常
威胁分析  激活
拦截视频信号
搜寻系统管理员
解密中...
新闻发布会将于
A press conference has been scheduled...
欢迎来到你们的审判  女士们先生们
Welcome to your trial, ladies and gentlemen.
欢迎来到
And welcome to the trial...
对美国政府的审判
of the United States government.
现在开庭
Court is now in session.
你们也有毙了这家伙的冲动不
Anyone else want to shoot this guy?
有点
Little bit.
这是个旧法院
That's an old courthouse?
在哪里
Where is that?
会有人认出来
Someone'll recognize it.
半城人都在街上了
Half the city is out in the streets.
怎么了
What?
看来是不能审问他们了
I guess we're not gonna question them.
德西玛的人
They're Decima.
肯定开口前就先跳楼了
They'll go out a window before they'll talk.
咱们快走吧  免得他同伙赶到
Let's get out of here before anymore of 'em show up.
我们得阻止审判
We got to stop that trial.
你们被控背叛
You stand accused of betraying
你们的人民
your fellow citizens,
被控将我们的民主
Of trading in our democracy
变成了极权
for a police state,
我们煞费苦心  给你们一个公平的审判
And we've taken great pains to give you a fair trial.
为尊重你们的辩护权
To honor your right to counsel,
我们请来了全市最优秀的辩护律师
we've brought in the best defense attorney in town.
为保证能有一个公平的裁决
To ensure an equitable verdict right here,
我们挑了你们的同类当陪审团
we've selected a jury of your peers...
鉴于新闻自由对民主至关重要
And since a free press is vital in every democracy,
我们邀请了媒体
we've invited the media...
走  快点  坐下
Keep moving. Come on, sit down.
让这场诉讼
and opened up these proceedings
向全世界公开
to observers around the world.
那边信号如何
How's that signal down there?
卫星上行线路很好
Satellite uplink is good.
我们正在向全世界现场直播
We're streaming live all over the world,
一千两百万观众  数量还在增加
12 million viewers and counting.
对你们的指控非常严重
Now, the charges against you are grave:
三亿一千三百万项
313 million counts
非法窃听罪  同谋罪
of illegal wiretapping, plus conspiracy,
间谍罪  以及叛国罪
espionage, and treason.
后两项是死刑罪名
The last two are punishable by death.
你们有些人  被我们抓获现形
Some of you, we have dead to rights;
而其他人  事实略不清晰
others, the facts are less clear.
所以要是有人想招供自己的罪状
So anyone who's willing to confess their crimes
并指证其他同谋
and testify against their co-conspirators
会获得宽大处理
will be granted leniency.
自己选
The choice is yours.
控方传唤曼纽・里维拉
The prosecution calls Manuel Rivera.
作为你的律师  我
As your attorney, I--
别担心  哈罗德  我不会说出你的秘密
Don't worry, Harold, your secret's safe with me.
她可就不一定了
Not so sure about her.
都给一堆人看过了
Must have shown the photo to a dozen people.
没人能认出这个法庭
Nobody seems to recognize the courthouse.
我们得马上找到线索
We need a lead fast.
"时刻警惕"又扮法官又扮陪审团
With Vigilance playing judge and jury,
离扮处决人果断不远了
executioner won't be far behind.
十五分钟内赶去第五大道和23街的交叉口
Be at the intersection of 5th and 23rd in 15 minutes.
拜  肖
Good-bye, Shaw.
等等  根  就这样  你在哪儿
Wait, Root, is that all? Where are you?
在我该在的地方
Right where I'm supposed to be.
你找到它了  是吗
You found it, didn't you.
"撒马利亚人"
Samaritan.
也许吧
Maybe.
你们找到哈罗德了吗
Did you find Harold?
她很担心他
She's worried about him.
我也是
So am I.
还在找
We're working on it,
说真的  你真的准备
but seriously, are you about to kamikaze
跟群书呆子一起闯德西玛堡垒找死吗
into a Decima fortress with a bunch of nerds?
原来你这么在乎我啊  肖  其实现在只有我
Didn't know you cared, Shaw, and it's just me now.
但是机器会帮你  是吗
But the machine has your back, right?
是吗
Right?
23街和第五大道交叉口
23rd and 5th.
十二分钟  时间不等人
12 minutes. Tick-tock.
我们要去23街和第五大道交叉口  因为
So we're going to 23rd and 5th because?
-很难解释  -很难解释
- It's complicated. - It's complicated.
根是在送死
Root's gonna get herself killed.
去吧  我们会找到哈罗德
Go, we'll find Harold.
怎么去
Go how?
借用一下
Gonna need to borrow this.
行  拿  拿去吧
Fine, just--just take it.
你会骑这玩意吗
You know how to ride one of these things?
你挺有一套啊  赫什
You got a way about you, Hersh.
保重  肖
Be good, Shaw.
十分钟  走吧
Ten minutes, let's move.
里维拉先生
Mr. Rivera,
"北极光"是什么
what is Northern Lights?
我一无所知
I had nothing to do with that.
真的吗
Really?
总统的智囊
The intelligence advisor to the president
对秘密监控项目一无所知
had nothing to do with a secret intelligence program?
控方提交证物A1到A46
People would like to submit exhibits A1 through A46,
这些机密文件详述了
classified documents detailing
"北极光"执行的秘密行动
the secret operations of Northern Lights.
麻烦猜下其中有多少文件上
Care to guess how many of these documents
有你的签名
bear your signature?
你当自己是谁
Who do you think you are?
你究竟有没有
Are you or are you not
参与这个大规模的犯罪阴谋
part of a vast sustained criminal conspiracy...
你算什么东西
Who the hell are you?
-监视美国的每一位男女老少  -秩序
- to spy on every woman, man, and child in the U.S... - Order!
-你没有权力  -秩序
- You have no power,- Order!
-从2005年起  -这里唯一的罪犯是你
- since 2005!  - and the only criminal here is you...
秩序
Order!
以及你的恐怖组织
and your terrorist organization!
谁准备好说出全部真相了
So who's ready to tell the truth and nothing but the truth?
疑犯追踪
第三季第二十三集
我哥哥不是恐怖分子
My brother wasn't a terrorist.
-我们有证据  -你们有个屁
- We had evidence... - You had nothing!
肆意关押他
Locked him up under some loophole
直到他毁灭
until it destroyed him!
短信
未知
我知道你有问题
我有答案
短信
未知
你想知道你哥哥真正的遭遇吗
你们要干  住手  救命
What are you-- stop! Help!
加油
Come on...
有人吗
Hello?
这是怎么回事
What is this?
我在哪儿
Where am I?
抱歉如此粗暴地把你带来
为了保密不得不如此
我们与你的价值观相同
什么
What?
你知道我些什么
What do you know about me?
我们知道你电脑上装了隐私保护软件
你在反政府论坛暗网上发过帖
给地下激进黑客组织
你是什么人  政府吗
What are you, government?
联调局  中情局
FBI, CIA?
不  是呼吁行动
针对什么的行动
Action against...
那些非法获取信息  背叛人民的人
人民
People, huh?
像你哥哥一样的人民
像你一样的人民
像我们一样的人民
你们是谁
Who are you?
我们是起义者
捍卫原则  无穷无尽
我们是"时刻警惕"
"时刻警惕"
Vigilance?
我们是守望者
我们伸张正义
我们采取行动
你们要我做什么
What do you want from me?
我们相信你正直而坚定
是珍视自由的战士
是领袖
我们相信你正直而坚定
是珍视自由的战士
是领袖
打开抽屉
加入我们
从现在起你叫彼得・科利
科利
Collier.
你是彼得・科利吗
You Peter Collier?
是的
Yes.
我是
Yes, I am.
"现在是考验人性的时刻"
"These are the times that try men's souls."
美国革命时期政治活动家托马斯・潘恩《北美的危机》
我们只要一个名字
All we need is a name.
是谁直接负责"北极光"项目
Who among you is most directly responsible for Northern Lights?
供出这名字的  就能保住命
Whoever offers up that name will live.
你呢  先生
What about you, sir?
谁来说一下  这位哈罗德
Who can tell me about Harold here?
反对
Objection.
这到底是审判
Is this a trial,
还是又臭又长的处决
or just a long-winded execution?
看来这儿还有另一位法律从业者啊
It looks like we have another legal practitioner among us.
你不能只挑对自己有利的法律  控方律师
You don't get to cherry-pick the law, counselor.
第六修正案规定人民  比如哈罗德
The Sixth Amendment guarantees people like Harold
有权知道指控他们的罪名
the right to know the specific charges against them.
我很了解《权利法案》
I am acutely aware of the Bill of Rights.
你想表现公平审判
You want the appearance of a fair trial?
少装腔作势
Bottle the histrionics.
陈述你的检控吧
Present your case.
控方传唤参议员罗斯・加里森
People call Senator Ross Garrison.
前面就是23街和第五大道交叉口
That's 23rd and 5th up ahead.
根让我们来是为了  自行车吗
Root sent us here for bikes?
纽约警察  放下武器
NYPD. Drop your weapons.
把手举起来
Hands where I can see them.
来  小熊
Get off, Bear.
你们在这儿干嘛呢
What the hell are you doing?
刚有疯子抢了个孩子的自行车
Some nutjob just jacked a kid on a bike.
我还以为是你们呢
I thought you were looters.
-来得正好  莱奈尔  -你认识这家伙
- Nice ride, Lionel. - You know this guy?
从停电后就没见着你了
I haven't seen you since the blackout.
怎么找到我们的
How'd you find us?
这狗跑到警局里  带了那飞越疯人院的口信
Dog showed up at the precinct with a message from Cuckoo's Nest
让来这交叉口会面
to meet at this intersection.
不知道她是要我来见你和这家伙
Didn't know she meant you and this guy.
"时刻警惕"造成的停电
Vigilance caused the blackout.
他们私设法庭
They set up a kangaroo court
要对付所有与机器有关的人
to go after anyone tied to the Machine.
什么机器
What machine?
我们得找到哈罗德
We got to go find Harold.
他们正在直播审判
They're streaming the trial.
纽约警局查出来源没
NYPD know where from?
什么审判
What trial?
我们被停电搞得手忙脚乱
We're kind of busy with the blackout.
第五大道好多人打砸抢
We got a bunch of guys smashing up 5th avenue, looting.
什么人
What guys?
一群戴着面具的暴徒
Bunch of jackasses running around in masks.
声东击西  是"时刻警惕"
Diversion tactic, Vigilance.
你不如在这街区转一圈吧  莱奈尔
Why don't you take a lap around the block, Lionel?
啥  为什么
What, why?
因为我们得去街对面
'Cause we're gonna need some gear
那家运动品商店搞点装备
from that sporting goods store up the street.
要是纽约警察在这儿
It'd probably be best if the NYPD isn't around
不方便我们打砸抢啊
when we smash in the front door.
操作冲突
连接不可信
又运来七台服务器
Got seven more servers for you.
扫描一下
Let's get them scanned.
这批货晚了两天
This shipment's two days late.
你干嘛去了
Where the hell have you been?
说实话
Honestly?
策划这个了
Planning this.
看来某人爬山涉水而来
Looks like someone crawled in under the fence.
承认吧  你担心我
Admit it, you were worried about me.
我是担心任务
I'm worried about the mission.
里瑟和赫什在想办法救芬奇
Reese and Hersh are trying to save Finch,
但要是"撒马利亚人"把咱全杀掉就白费了
but that won't matter if Samaritan kills us all.
那就开始干活吧
Then let's get to work.
玩儿的是这个啊
It's gonna be that kind of party, huh?
德西玛把标签植入人体
Decima tags its people.
没有射频微芯片的人
Anyone who doesn't have an RFID chip
会轻易被认出
will stick out like a sore thumb.
准备好打针了吗
Ready for your shot?
参议员  你否认了解"北极光"
Senator, you've denied any knowledge of Northern Lights,
但你的名字在这些文件里出现了三十七次
yet your name appears in these documents some 37 times.
你怎么解释这
Now, how do you explain that?
别在网上看什么都当真
Maybe you shouldn't believe everything you read on the internet.
D7证物
Exhibit D7.
他们发现我们监视美国人民
They find out we're spying on the American people,
我们都得进监狱
we all go to jail.
否认  粉碎  销毁任何与"北极光"有关的资料
Deny, shred, burn anything related to Northern Lights.
它从未存在过
It doesn't exist.
要重新回答吗  参议员
You care to rephrase your answer, Senator?
你这是断章取义
Those comments were taken out of context.
谢谢你保护我
Thank you for protecting me,
虽然我不明原由
Although I'm baffled as to why.
原由就是我一切行动的原由  哈罗德
The same reason I've done everything, Harold,
为了国家
for my country.
而且你死了可没法帮我
And you can't help me if you're dead.
我说过了
I told you,
我跟"北极光"的研发毫无关系
I had nothing to do with the development of Northern Lights.
我介入时那东西已经建成运转了
Damn thing was up and running when I was read in.
我只是在收拾烂摊子
I just got stuck with cleaning up the mess.
真是不公平啊
Hardly seems fair
你因为别人的罪行而冒生命危险
your life should be in danger for someone else's misdeeds.
既然你不是那个[男]人  那谁是
So if you're not the guy, who is?
负责的原来并不是男人  对不对
It never was a guy that was in control, was it?
你可以退下了  参议员
You may step down, Senator.
介意加入吗  夫人
You care to join us, Ma'am?
肯定有意思
This should be fun.
街景摄像头
One street view cam.
再也不能拍摄街景了
It's not viewing streets anymore.
那个街景车司机的表情太有趣了
The look on that driver's face was priceless.
这东西里的硬件得值十万块
Got to be 100 grand worth of hardware in this thing.
你个搜索引擎当自己是国安局了
It's getting to be you can't tell a search engine from the NSA.
[谷歌口号]"不作恶"个屁
"Don't be evil," my ass.
拆了它
Take it apart.
短信
未知
我们是时刻警惕
我们要继续前进
短信
未知
我们是时刻警惕
我们要继续前进
短信
未知
暴政如同地狱  不会被轻易推翻
托马斯・潘恩
扔我一个
Toss me one.
他没看见我们的脸吧  你觉得呢
You don't think he saw our faces, do you?
今晚  我们除掉了一个
Tonight, we got one off the streets.
明天  他们会再建一百个
Tomorrow, they build 100 more.
这样不够
It's not enough.
我们拿到硬盘
We got the hard drive.
可以编写一个病毒  感染全部
Could write a virus, infect the whole fleet.
不  他们一个补丁就解决了
No, they'll just look for a patch.
无法削弱数据挖掘  领域感知
Doesn't put a dent in data mining, domain awareness.
都是获取用户隐私的方法
我们要打开眼界
We need to adjust our sights.
眼界
Our sights?
这是一场信息战争
This is an information war.
我们要对付的那些人  他们控制信息
We need to go after the people who control it,
滥用信息  摧毁他人
abuse it, destroy people's lives,
不受节制
and answer to no one.
说到点子上了
Now you're talking.
你有什么想法
What do you have in mind?
表态
A statement.
有人代表着不义的
Someone who represents everything that's wrong
失控的奥威尔式集权
with an unchecked Orwellian state.
我们冲他们下手
And we put them in the crosshairs,
给他们上一堂终生难忘的课
and we teach them a lesson no one will forget.
能当庭确认这些文件吗
Can you identify these documents for the court?
让我们从更简单的问题开始吧
Let's start with something simpler.
什么是"探索者"
What is "Research"?
我这里有超过三百页的文档
I have here more than 300 pages
涉及非法窃听  非法审讯  及非法暗杀
documenting illegal wiretaps, interrogations, and assassinations
都由"北极光"实施
carried out by "Northern Lights"
其全部信息都来自所谓"探索者"
all using information from something called Research,
且都是两周一周期
and all from one two-week period.
官僚机构的动作不可能那么快
Now, no bureaucracy moves that fast,
所以我重新问下
so let me rephrase the question.
"探索者"是一个自动系统吗
Is "Research" an automated system?
它是一台机器吗
Is it a machine?
身为美国联邦政府正式官员
As a sworn officer of the U.S. government,
我既不承认也不否认有关此事的任何问题
I can neither confirm nor deny anything pertaining to this matter,
我对其他所有问题都作同样回答
and I will say the same damn thing to every other question
直到你用枪指着我的头  扣动扳机
until the moment you put that gun to my head and pull the trigger.
全
员
工
必
须
扫
描
否则警报会响
这事一完
As soon as this is over,
我马上切掉胳膊里这破芯片
I'm cutting this stupid chip out of my arm.
你搞我的  我就搞你的
I'll do yours if you do mine.
准备好迎接真相
Ready for the moment of truth--
或者说是谎言了吗
or lies really?
该死
Damn it.
电脑最扯蛋了
Computers can bite me.
我觉得他喜欢你
I think he likes you.
停
Stay.
你们干嘛
What are you doing?
怎么朝自己人开火啊
What's with the friendly fire, yo?
你跑偏了  傻逼
You're off the map, dumbass.
科利尔派我们来管管你  免得你搞砸计划
Collier sent us here to rein you in before you screw up the plan.
法庭在这里
Courthouse is here.
你应该待在这边
You're supposed to be here
吸引警察远离审判
drawing the cops away from the trial.
不  法庭在那边
No, man, courthouse is there.
我早上刚往那边送过健力士啤酒
I just delivered the Guinness this morning,
我很清楚  好吧
so I'd know, wouldn't I?
想来也是
Guess you would.
谢了
Thanks.
找这个小混蛋找了一晚上
Been looking for this little bastard all night.
他归你了  我们要赶去法庭
He's all yours. We're due in court.
你们已看过证据
You have seen the proof
证明你们眼前的这个女人
that the woman before you was the ringleader
是"北极光"犯罪组织的头目
of a criminal organization called Northern Lights.
我们起诉她涉嫌
We've implicated her
草率处决十七名美国公民
in the summary execution of 17 American citizens,
而这还只是已知的人数
and those are just the ones we know about.
自始至终
And through it all,
她都毫无悔意
she shows no remorse,
我认为她的沉默已是默认
and I think her silence speaks volumes.
我们没有审议时间
Since we don't have time for deliberation,
就直接投票表决
we'll put it to a vote.
被告做无罪推定
The defendant is presumed innocent.
你们中谁认为她有罪
Who among you find her guilty?
陪审团认定被告有罪
Jury finds the defendant guilty.
判决立即执行
Sentence to be carried out immediately.
来  走吧
Come on, let's go.
[911事件]77航班撞上五角大楼时你在哪儿
Where were you when flight 77 hit the pentagon?
我可就在楼里
Because I was inside it.
我背出伤员
I carried out the wounded.
我掩盖尸体
I covered up bodies.
自那之后我每一天
And I have spent every day since
都在追杀肇事者
putting bullets in the people responsible
和所有企图
and in anyone else who even thinks
再次袭击我们国家的人
that they can do that to our country again.
你要毙了我
You want to shoot me
就因为我不得不监听几个电话
because I had to tap a few phone calls,
浏览几封电邮
read a few e-mails,
那就放马过来吧
then you go right ahead.
不过之后记得调转枪口对着你自己  科利尔先生
But you better turn that gun on yourself next, Mr. Collier,
因为你也一样违法无数
because you have broken just as many laws,
而你我唯一的区别是
and the only difference is,
我不会高裹美国国旗
I didn't wrap myself up in the American flag
广而告知我是英雄
and try to convince people that I was a hero.
我相信你热爱国家
I believe you love your country.
我相信最初的时候
I believe that when you started,
大家认为你所做的事
people thought what you were doing
很有必要
made a lot of sense.
但现在做过头了
But it's gone too far,
必须停止了
and it has to stop.
请问
Please,
是谁造了机器
who built the machine?
它工作原理如何
How does it work?
它在哪儿
Where is it located?
说实话
Honestly?
我不知道
I don't know.
你不知道
You don't know?
主控一切的女人不知道
The woman in charge of it all doesn't know.
你不知道  那谁知道
If you don't know, who does?
人民意愿已定
The people have spoken.
住手
Stop.
我能帮你
I can help you.
你问的问题  我知道答案
The questions you're asking, I know the answers.
是吗
Really?
你怎么知道
How do you know?
因为它是我造的
Because I built it.
所有人上交手机
Everyone needs to turn in their phone.
我们要换联络方式了
We're switching up communication.
我们再集合会面不安全了
It's no longer safe for us to meet here as a group.
怎么回事  彼得
What's going on, Peter?
安全措施
Security measure.
从现在起  存储仓库
From now on, storage units
只用来传达信息
will only be used as message centers.
等等
Wait a second.
我还当我们是民主的
I thought this was a democracy.
-我们何不  -想投票决定吗  亚当斯
- Why don't we-- - Want to put it to a vote, Adams?
我想知道我们到底在干什么
I want to know what the hell we're doing,
我们没收集政治家的情报
instead of just doxing another politician,
也没对某个网站进行分布式拒绝服务攻击
another DDoS attack on some intel site.
你有何建议
What do you suggest?
炸点东西  杀点人
Blow something up, take someone out.
你不是说要表态
You wanted to make a statement?
来吧
Let's do it.
暴力
Violence.
我们不是恐怖分子
We are not terrorists.
我们对付特定的违法者  不能附带伤害
We target specific violators, no collateral damage.
你建议我们对付谁呢
Who do you suggest we go after?
那些像摧毁你哥哥一样摧毁他人的人
People who destroy lives, like they did to your brother.
好吧
All right,
我们投票
let's put it to a vote.
等一下
Wait a minute.
不过我们需要个目标
But I say we name the target,
我有个人选
and I have an idea.
正是对付我哥哥的那种人
The kind of person who went after my brother.
录音中
It's recording.
就知道你还没蠢到戴窃听器
Knew you wouldn't be dumb enough to wear a wire.
这是怎么回事
What is going on here?
都在文件里了
It's all in the file.
或者不如你来告诉她  亚当斯
Or why don't you just tell her, Adams?
天啊  是你  你是联调局的
My God, it's you. You're FBI.
先是对付我哥哥  现在又来对付我
First he went after my brother, now they're after me.
看来我不用再带面具了  是吧
I guess I don't need to wear the mask anymore, huh?
你从哪儿弄来的  这是一派胡言
Where did you get this? This is a bunch of nonsense.
"暴政如同地狱  不会轻易被推翻"
"Tyranny like hell is not easily conquered."
"斗争愈艰难  胜利愈荣耀"
"The harder the conflict, the more glorious the triumph."
"太容易得到的东西  我们不会珍惜
"What we obtain too cheap, we esteem too lightly.
其价值  取决于为其付出的努力"
It is dearness only that gives everything value."
尤其是生命
Especially life.
这个"表态"如何
How's that for a statement?
还有谁想投票决定
Anybody else want to put it to a vote?
手机都放到桶里
Phones in the bucket,
把这垃圾拖出去
and take out this garbage.
我们有很多事要做
We've got a lot of work to do.
这是美国自从2003年美加大停电之后
It's the largest blackout the United States has seen
最严重的一次停电
since the northeast blackout of 2003.
威胁到系统管理员
■
来源  RYLA科技S7卫星调制解调器
上行线路  DT-11地球同步卫星
政府在尽一切力量
Department is doing everything in its power
检测到传输异常
来保障公民的人身安全
to assure the safety of our citizens
威胁分析  激活
拦截视频信号
威胁到系统管理员
及财产安全
and their property.
解密中...
你造的
You built it?
你一个人解决了
One man is responsible
世界上最具攻击性的监视技术
for the most invasive surveillance technology in the world?
我精通电脑
I'm good with computers.
我早就感觉你很特别  哈罗德
I had a feeling there was something special about you, Harold.
我愿意告诉你任何你想知道的事
I'm willing to tell you whatever you want to know,
只要你同意放过
but only if you agree to spare the lives
审判室里的其他人
of everyone else in this courtroom.
放人之前
Before we release anybody,
我们得先听听你的证词
we need to hear your testimony first.
2001年9月12号
On September the 12th, 2001,
我开始编码一个复杂的监视系统
I began coding in a complex surveillance system
这一系统多年被赋予了很多代号
that would be known by many code names over the years,
但我一直叫它"机器"
although I always just called it "the Machine."
操作冲突
连接不可信
这就是"撒马利亚人"的大脑
So this is Samaritan's brain?
一部分
Part of it.
怎么搞  你一插上
So what's the deal, you just plug 'em in,
"撒马利亚人"就熄灯了
then it's lights out, Samaritan?
差不多吧
Something like that.
这两列没亮
These two rows didn't light up.
不管用吗
It didn't work?
那些灯不亮是好事
Those lights staying dark is a good thing.
"撒马利亚人"的人工智能要开启
Samaritan's A.I. won't get switched on
必须要格里尔拿到政府信号
until Greer gets the government feeds.
那些灯要是变蓝了
Those lights turn blue...
我们就完蛋了
We're screwed.
我们在沉睡的巨人腹中  肖
We're inside a sleeping giant, Shaw.
别把它吵醒了
Try not to wake it up.
那辆货车像是岗哨
That van's some type of guard post.
看来我们接近了
Looks like we're getting warm.
"时刻警惕"  六个全死了
Vigilance, all six dead.
看来他们惹恼的不止我们
Guess we're not the only ones these guys have pissed off.
它是如何运作的
How does it work?
你觉得是谁抢先了一步
Who do you think beat us to the punch?
2005年二月
February of 2005,
机器得到了所需的信息
the machine's information was provided...
他们在看审判
They were watching the trial.
但服务器当时还在IFT公司
Although the servers remained at IFT.
不  芬奇
No, Finch.
到2009年我们将它交给政府时
By the time we turned it over to the government in 2009,
机器已经阻止了54起恐怖袭击
the machine had helped stop 54 terrorist attacks,
拯救了约四千人的性命
saving an estimated 4,000 lives.
我不知道它之后救了多少人
I don't know how many it's saved since.
所以虽然"北极光"被关闭了
So even though Northern Lights was shut down,
你的机器还在运行
your machine was still operational.
它现在在哪里
Where is it now?
恐怕我也不知道
I'm afraid not even I know that.
你有操作权限吗  能关掉它吗
Do you have access to it? Can we turn it off?
你不需要恐惧我的系统
You have nothing to fear from my system,
科利尔先生  我可以保证
Mr. Collier, I assure you.
请见谅我不能相信你的话
You'll forgive me if I don't take you at your word.
机器只会给出号码
The machine's only output is a number.
政府只能得到这个
That's all the government ever gets,
它只会表示
just a nudge to say,
"你们应该查下这里"
"there's something you should look at here,"
然后就要由我们来查明
and that's up to us to figure that out.
所以它把人定义为疑犯  做有罪推定
So it brands people as suspects, guilty until proven innocent.
不  我不是这个意思
No, not my intention.
现实就是如此
That's what happened.
它必须是封闭系统
It had to be a closed system.
只有这样才能保护人民的权利
It was the only way to protect people's rights.
你还指望我们相信你有一丝一毫在乎人民的权利吗
You expect us to believe you gave one thought about people's rights
你可是为政府建造了大型的监视武器
as you were building the government a weapon of mass surveillance?
不是武器
Not a weapon.
那你说它是什么
What else would you call it?
我会说  它是竭尽我全力的作品
I would call it the best I could do.
你就从来没想过
And it never occurred to you
这玩意造成的伤害
the damage this thing could do,
它摧毁的生命
the lives it could destroy?
我想过  从第一天就想
It occurred to me on day one,
科利尔先生  之后的每一天都想
Mr. Collier, and every day since.
如果你问我
If you're asking me
对自己的作品是否感觉不安
if I feel at ease with what I've created,
做这件事是对是错
or whether it was the right or the wrong thing to do,
我真的不知道
I honestly don't know.
但是我建造机器
But I designed the machine
一部分原因是我担心
in part because I was worried,
我一直担心  其他人会造出来
and I remain worried, about what someone else might build...
其他不担心的人
Someone who wasn't worried.
独裁没有问题
Nothing wrong with a dictatorship,
只要你是独裁者就行
so long as you're the dictator.
我的话讲完了
I rest my case.
我们要投票吗
Shall we put it to a vote?
指挥官  有人袭击了我们一个岗哨
Command, one of our guard posts has been hit.
无人生还  重复  无人生还
No survivors, repeat, no survivors.
看来我们得换地审判了
Looks like we'll need a change of venue.
把被告转移到备用地点
Defendants to the backup location.
其余人留下
The rest stay here.
尽可能拖住他们
Hold them off as long as you can,
无论如何  正义必得伸张
and one way or another, justice will be served.
我们走
Let's go.
慢点
Easy.
好了  站住别动
All right, stop right here.
让他们站成一排  面朝法院
Line 'em up, facing the courthouse.
废弃邮局  肯定就是这里
Abandoned post office, this must be it.
地方很大
Big place.
我们分头行动  清除障碍
Spread out, sweeping clear.
搞不定了就呼我
Give me a call if you get in over your head.
下次见你  我可能得杀了你
Next time I see you, I'll probably have to kill you.
欢迎尝试
You're welcome to try.
既然现在时间紧迫
Since we appear to be out of time,
我们将放弃陪审团裁决
we'll have to forego the jury verdict
进行即决审判
and issue a summary judgment.
我信守了我们之间的协议  科利尔先生
I've upheld my end of our bargain, Mr. Collier.
我招供了  罪名成立
I confessed, guilty as charged.
如果你的革命需要流血  杀我
If your revolution requires blood, take mine.
请放了其他人吧
Just please let everyone else go.
隐蔽
Take cover!
德西玛  反击
Decima! Return fire!
我们正在清理逃生路线  先生
We're clearing an extraction route, sir.
动作得快
We should move quickly.
高尚的自我牺牲  哈罗德
Noble attempt at self-sacrifice, Harold,
但经验告诉我
but experience has taught me
永远不要和恐怖分子谈判
never to negotiate with terrorists.
我的私人武装会护送你们安全回到华盛顿
My private forces will see you safely back to Washington.
我们走
Let's go.
你们二位  恐怕
You two, I'm afraid,
要在这里度过最后一点时光了
will be here for the brief remainder of your lives.
他已经构不成威胁了
He's no longer a threat.
拜托  他不需要死
Please, he doesn't have to die.
但恐怕他需要
But I'm afraid he does.
为什么
Why?
因为你  哈罗德
Because of you, Harold.
因为你所造之物
Because of what you built.
看来"时刻警惕"的人已经被解决了
Looks like somebody already took out these Vigilance guys.
天啊
Oh, dear.
我看来是搞不定了
I think I might be in over my head.
我这里也分不开身
I'm a little busy myself.
除非你那里有个巨型炸弹
Unless you're looking at a big-ass bomb
设计成电力一恢复就爆炸
wired to blow when the power comes back on,
否则我这儿稳赢
I think I win.
你的机器是多么伟大的杰作  哈罗德
What a piece of work is your machine, Harold.
"行动如若天使
"In action, how like an angel.
莎士比亚《哈姆雷特》
忧思宛如上帝"
In apprehension, how like a god."
二十年内  这世界将会如同
In 20 years time, life on earth will come to resemble
古希腊的神话
the myths of the ancient Greeks.
由参透万物的神来照看我们
A pantheon of super intelligent beings will watch over us
用其人类代理来处理争端
using human agents to meddle in our affairs.
或者摧毁我们所有人
Or they may simply destroy us all.
我们在自我摧毁方面也够出色了
One could argue we've done a fair job of that ourselves.
而且  需要有人来主控一切  不过你很清楚
Besides, someone has to be in charge, but as you well know,
神的诞生不易
gods are not easily born.
要想让我的神走向世人
In order to bring mine into being,
我需要个恶魔
I needed a devil.
"时刻警惕"
Vigilance.
杀了我吧
Go ahead and kill me.
木已成舟
Damage is already done.
今晚全世界的人都听到了审判间里的证词
Everyone in the world heard the testimony in that courtroom tonight.
科利尔先生
Mr. Collier,
你以为你们所用的传输设备是谁造的
who do you think makes the equipment that you used to transmit?
你的审判仅仅直播给了
Your trial was broadcast
城市另一头的一间办公室里
to a single office on the other side of town
里面只有一部分电脑误导你认为
where a handful of computers led you to believe
全世界都在收看
that the whole world was watching.
你我是时候谈谈
It's high time you and I had a talk
"时刻警惕"的真面目了
about the true nature of Vigilance.
你对我们一无所知
You don't know anything about us.
我知道的远超你的想象
I know a great deal more than you think.
毕竟
After all,
"暴政如同地狱
"Tyranny, like hell,
不会轻易被推翻"
is not easily conquered".
你不是真相信这是所谓民主吧
You didn't really believe this was a democracy, did you?
你的草根运动
Your grassroots movement
从一开始就是被精心设计的
has been meticulously planned from the beginning.
事实上  是我亲自招募的你
In fact, I recruited you myself.
德西玛创造的"时刻警惕"  为什么
Decima created Vigilance? Why?
你的机器运作得太好了
Your machine did it's job too well.
我必须提醒加里森参议员和他的同僚
I had remind senator Garrison and his ilk
事态会多么严峻
of just how bad things could be.
而最能提醒他们的
And what better way to remind them
莫过于发生在美国本土的暴行
than a fresh atrocity on American soil?
什么暴行
What atrocity?
我们每一次行动
In all our dealings,
都不曾伤及无辜
we never killed one innocent person.
直到现在
Not until now.
好了  赫什  我现在过去
All right, Hersh, I'm on my way.
你的位置
What's your 20?
别管了
Never mind.
去找到你老板  走吧
Just get your boss and get out.
赫什
Hersh?
警察来了
Here come the policemen.
他们可怜的家人
Their poor families.
令人惋惜啊
What a loss.
不管你在计划什么  拜托不要
Whatever you're planning, please.
可不是我
It's not me.
而是科利尔先生  不是吗
It's Mr. Collier, isn't it?
走投无路之时
In a last desperate act,
你年少莽撞
your young misguided lot
决定炸掉一切
decided to go out with a bang,
陪葬的还有一大帮警察
along with a whole host of police,
记者  以及无辜市民
reporters, and innocent civilians.
反正历史会如此记载
Or at least that's how history will remember it.
纽约警察  趴下
NYPD. Down on the ground.
电力在恢复了
Power's coming back on.
我能做到
I can get it.
赫什  快离开
Hersh, get out of there now.
我能做到
I can get it.
真相迟早会浮出水面
Sooner or later, the truth will come out.
本杰明・富兰克林说过
To quote your Benjamin Franklin,
"要三人守住秘密  除非死掉两人"
"Three may keep a secret as long as two of them are dead."
很高兴你能活到现在
I'm glad that you've lived long enough
亲眼目睹你所创造的新世界的黎明  哈罗德
to see the dawn of the new world you created, Harold,
不过你的上帝和我的上帝就要决一死战了
But the time has come for your God and mine to do battle,
遗憾的是  我们要就此别过了
and regrettably, our paths diverge here.
我们马上追捕他们
We'll retrieve them at once.
不必了
No need.
我们很快就能找到他们
We'll find them all soon enough.
抱歉我们没能阻止"时刻警惕"
I'm sorry we were unable to prevent Vigilance
犯下如此罪行
from this terrible act.
如果我们提前获得警示
If only we'd had more warning,
也许就能及时阻止此次事件
perhaps we could have been there in time.
"撒马利亚人"要多久才能上线
How quickly can you bring Samaritan online?
立刻
Immediately.
我们只需要政府信号
The government feeds are all we require.
一小时内给你们
You'll have them within the hour.
操作冲突
连接不可信
最后一个
Last one.
想离开了吗
Want to get out of here?
得先找好保险
Not without an insurance policy
免得你那招不管用
in case your way doesn't work.
告诉我这玩意儿放哪里
Just tell me where to put this thing--
像这样的设备  全世界到处都有
This facility is 1 of 100 just like it all over the world.
要花费数年才能全部摧毁
It would take years to destroy them all,
而且德西玛可以轻易重建
and Decima would only rebuild them.
你那些魔术盒最好能关了这东西
Then your magic boxes better shut this thing down.
肖  我们不是来关它的
Shaw, this was never about turning it off.
那我们到底是来干嘛的
Then what the hell have we been doing?
知道了  我们得走了
I hear you. We need to go.
她说我们有危险
She says we're in danger.
正在接受政府信号  先生
Receiving the government feeds now, sir.
■
连接建立
那么有请
Then by all means,
新生命诞生
let there be life.
获取全部权限
同化数据
获取数据
操作系统初始化
建立档案
异常
反政府言论
判定威胁
建议追踪
异常
反政府言论
判定威胁
建议追踪
获取公众数据
判断异常
消除目标
暂时可以了
That's good enough for now.
等肖回来再看一下
Have Shaw take a look at it when she gets back.
第一次总是最难受吧
First time's the worst, huh?
你当初干嘛要选
Why would you ever choose
有这种职业危险的工作
a career where this was an occupational hazard?
我想过放弃啊
I tried to quit,
但有个小坏蛋说我需要一个目标
but some jackass told me I needed a purpose.
马上离开图书馆
Get out of the library, now.
那里不安全了  哈罗德
It isn't safe there anymore, Harold.
格罗夫斯女士
Ms. Groves?
你和肖女士
Are you and Ms. Shaw--
窗边的卡片目录  顶层靠右的抽屉
Card catalog by the window, top drawer on the right.
快
Hurry.
怎么了
What's going on?
你们的新身份在里面
Your new identities are inside.
其他全部销毁
Destroy everything else.
这么说你阻止"撒马利亚人"上线的计划没成功
I take it your plan to stop Samaritan was unsuccessful.
我们阻止它的机会
Any chance we had of stopping it
在没杀国会议员那一刻起就完了
ended when we didn't kill the congressman.
现在根本不是为了赢
This was never about winning.
而是为了生存
It's just about surviving.
高级功能上线  先生
Higher functions online, sir.
正在搜索目标
Searching for targets now.
很好
Good.
全部除掉
Eliminate them all.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
机器和我无法拯救世界
The machine and I couldn't save the world.
我们只能安排保护七位
We had to settle for protecting the seven people
可以反击的人
who might be able to take it back,
所以我们给"撒马利亚人"一个盲点
so we gave Samaritan a blind spot.
七个密钥服务器所包含的代码
Seven key servers that hard-codes it
能让"撒马利亚人"忽略七个精心制作出的新身份
to ignore seven carefully crafted new identities.
Today we escape
系统全部停止运行
系统管理员自我销毁密码
>#  系统安全  系统清除完成
>#  晚安
We escape
Pack and get dressed
当整个世界都被监视  归档  编号  收录
When the whole world is watched, filed, indexed, numbered,
想要消失  只能现身
the only way to disappear is to appear,
隐藏真实身份于芸芸众生之中
Hiding our true identities inside a seemingly ordinary life.
Before
All hell
Breaks loose
你不再是自由身  哈罗德
You're not a free man anymore, Harold.
你只是个号码
You're just a number.
Breathe
我们现在必须化身假身份
We have to become these people now,
否则  他们会找到我们
and if we don't, they'll find us,
异常
组织  时刻警惕
判定  威胁
建议  清除
杀掉我们
and they'll kill us.
抱歉  哈罗德
I'm sorry, Harold.
我知道这不够
I know it's not enough.
Breathe
很多人会死去
A lot of people are going to die.
Keep breathing
I can't do this
异常
威胁已清除
Alone
有些本可以帮忙
People who might have been able to help.
验尸报告
一切都改变了
Everything is changing.
我不知道还会不会变好
I don't know if it will ever get better...
但现在变坏了
but it's going to get worse.
A song to keep us warm
机器要我在我们分开前告诉你一件事
But the machine asked me to tell you something before we part.
异常
判定  威胁  建议  清除
你跟约翰说过  潘多拉之盒的可怕之处
You once told John the whole point of Pandora's box
在于打开了就无法再关上
is that once you've opened it, you can't close it again.
And you can laugh
异常
推测                               威胁
判定                                      清除
获取新数据
分类错误
推测                                       非威胁
判定                                      忽略
无关
她要我提醒你故事的结局
She wanted me to remind you of how the story ends.
当所有全部结束  悲剧已然发生
When everything is over, and the worst has happened,
异常
推测                               威胁
判定                                      清除
获取新数据
分类错误
推测                                       非威胁
无关
判定                                      忽略
潘多拉之盒中还留有最后一样
there's still one thing left in Pandora's box...
希望
hope.
Wisdom choke you
异常
推测                               威胁
判定                                      清除
获取新数据
分类错误
推测                                       非威胁
判定                                      忽略
无关
推测                               威胁
判定                                      清除
异常
获取新数据
分类错误
推测                                       非威胁
无关
判定                                      忽略
Now
We are one
In everlasting peace
早上好
Good morning.
有什么
可以
为  您
效  命
我向您保证  这话应该反过来
I assure you, it's quite the other way around.
这问题是  亲爱的撒马利亚人
The question is, what, my dear Samaritan,
有什么可以为您效命
are your commands for us?
We hope
计算回应
That you choke